MUSTAPHA GHANNOUCHI

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

24 Hannibal st , 1124 Djedeida , Tunisia

+21622034737

mustaphaghannouchi@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Enthusiastic, dynamic and creative software developer with almost 2 years of experience working on large scale systems.

With top-notch coding skills, maintained and bug fixed functionalities, decreased app memory consumption (memory intensive Java powered process), improved some of the existent functionalities and created new ones on the Datahub application at Neoxam.

As freelancer, worked on 2 web projects, designed backend APIs reducing time consumption of signup and payment processes and ensured 98% on-time tasks completion.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science

2016 - 2020

Faculty of Economics and Management of Tunis

 Relevant Coursework: Operating Systems Architecture, C , C++ and C# Programming I & II, Web Page Development, Relational Database Design & SQL, Java Programming

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software developer

Sep, 2020 - Present

Neoxam Tunisia

- Corrective and evolutionary maintenance of the data management solution Neoxam DataHub
- Technologies: Java core, Java Swing, Tomcat, Wildfly, mysql, SQL Server, Oracle, Postgres, Bitbucket, Bamboo, Jenkins, Artificatory

Software developer intern

Feb, 2020 - Jul, 2020

Neoxam Tunisia

- Developed for my senior year graduation project a desktop application that automates the conversion of virtual machines databases (Oracle, SqlServer, Postgres...) into mysql databse to run them on local environements
- Technoologies: Python, Kivy Framework

PROJECTS

- MyMotherAgency: Backend APIs (Paypal, Stripe, Razor Pay), Frontend interfaces
 Technologies: Node JS, express, React JS, Styled components, Firebase NoSql Database
- Jetons Canada eCommerce website, Wordpress CMS
- Zaril Tech , technology news blog Technologie : ReactJS , Next JS , GraphQL , Tailwind CSS

- Uber app clone Todo App (Training project: ReactJS)
 - Technologie: ReactJS, Tailwind CSS, NextJS, Firebase, SpringBoot
- Academic project: Fullstack ecommerce website using ReactJS, Express, NodeJS, MongoDB,
 SpingBoot Microservices, Jenkins, Docker, SonarQube

TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML, CSS (TailwindCSS), Javascript (ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, NextJS), Java core, Java swing, SpringBoot, Tomcat.
- Database: mysql, SQL Server, Oracle, Postgres, NoSql Firebase, MongoDB.
- Version control: Git, Github, BitBucket
- CI/CD: Bamboo, Jenkins, Docker.
- · Binary repository manager: Artifactory, Nexus
- Mobile : Flutter (Basic Knowledge)

LANGUAGES

English: IntermediateFrench: BilingualArabic: Native

VOLUNTEER WORK

Volunteer

Tunisian Red Crescent

Volunteered during Covid 19 vaccination open days

Member

JCI

Social projects trying to improve the life of our local community.